There's an old riddle used by psychologists which shows the gender bias people have when it comes to the types of jobs men and women do.
有一个被心理学家使用的古老谜题，它展示了人们在涉及男性和女性所从事的工作类型时存在的性别偏见（gender bias）。
Let's see if you can do it: A father and son are in an accident.
我们来看看你能否解开它：一对父子遭遇了一场事故。
The father dies.
父亲去世了。
The surgeon refuses to operate on the injured boy saying, "The boy is my son."
外科医生（surgeon）拒绝为受伤的男孩做手术，说道：“这个男孩是我的儿子。”
Can you explain?
你能解释这是怎么回事吗？
According to research done in 2012 by Mikaela Wapman and Deborah Belle at the University of Boston, only 14% of those surveyed were able to imagine that a surgeon could be a woman.
根据波士顿大学（University of Boston）的米凯拉・瓦普曼（Mikaela Wapman）和黛博拉・贝尔（Deborah Belle）在2012年所做的研究，在接受调查的人中，只有14%的人能够想到外科医生可能是女性。
Stereotypes about who should do what type of job are mirrored in the makeup of the workforce.
关于谁应该从事何种工作的刻板印象（Stereotypes）在劳动人口构成中有所体现。
For example, the BBC recently reported that only 10% of UK engineers are women.
例如，BBC最近报道称，英国的工程师中只有10%是女性。
That's the lowest in Europe, where most other countries put the figure at around 20%.
这在欧洲是比例最低的，在大多数其他欧洲国家中，这一比例约为20%。
That’s still only a fifth.
即便如此也仅仅是五分之一。
And it’s not just engineering either.
而且也不只是工程领域如此。
In August 2017, Prof Polly Arnold of Edinburgh University found that only 10% of the top jobs in Scottish science, technology, engineering and mathematics are held by women.
2017年8月，爱丁堡大学（University of Edinburgh）的波莉・阿诺德（Polly Arnold）教授发现，在苏格兰科学、技术、工程和数学领域的高级职位中，只有10%由女性担任。
So why is it that women don't go into scientific jobs?
那么，为什么女性不从事科学领域的工作呢？
Sophie, a girl from a school in Hertfordshire, England, who studied engineering at secondary school, says, "It starts at a young age… girls are put in a corner with a doll while boys play with trucks and cars."
索菲（Sophie）是一名来自英国赫特福德郡（Hertfordshire）一所学校的女孩，她在中学时学习工程专业，她说：“这种情况从小就开始了……当男孩们玩卡车和汽车时，女孩们却被安排在角落里玩洋娃娃。”
There's also the lack of female role models.
还存在缺乏女性榜样（role models）的问题。
“I don’t think they get as much visibility as they deserve,” says Priyanka Dhopade, one of the Women’s Engineering Society top 50 under-35 women engineers.
“我认为她们没有得到应有的曝光度（visibility），”普里扬卡・多帕德（Priyanka Dhopade）说道，她是女性工程协会（Women’s Engineering Society）评选出的35岁以下50位杰出女工程师之一。
She says that it would make a huge difference for young girls to have someone to look up to and say ‘I want to be like her.’
她说，对于年轻女孩来说，有一个值得敬仰并说出“我想成为像她那样的人”的人会对她产生巨大的影响。
Regardless of their lack of visibility, a number of pioneering women have paved the way to amazing discoveries.
尽管她们缺乏曝光度，但许多先驱女性为惊人的发现铺平了道路（paved the way）。
Let us not forget Marie Curie, whose groundbreaking work made her the first Nobel Prize winner in two different fields: physics and chemistry.
我们不要忘记玛丽・居里（Marie Curie），她开创性的（groundbreaking）工作使她成为在两个不同领域（物理学和化学）获得诺贝尔奖的第一人。
There's Rajaa Cherkaoui El Moursli, who overcame any number of cultural prejudices to play a key role in the discovery of the Higgs-Boson particle.
还有拉贾・切尔卡维・埃尔・穆尔斯利（Rajaa Cherkaoui El Moursli），她战胜了诸多文化偏见，在希格斯玻色子的发现中发挥了关键作用。
And Soyeon Yi, who became the first South Korean astronaut in 2008, and who hoped her success would inspire more women.
以及李素妍（Soyeon Yi），她在2008年成为了首位韩国女宇航员，并且她希望自己的成功能够激励更多的女性。
Quite clearly, women have made momentous contributions to science, technology and engineering.
很明显，女性对科学、技术和工程做出了重大的（momentous）贡献。
If these achievements were more celebrated, it may encourage girls and young women to consider science as their future career.
如果这些成就能够得到更多的赞誉，这可能会鼓励女孩和年轻女性将科学领域视为她们未来的职业。
And as more women start to do these jobs, more people might instantly recognise that the surgeon in the riddle is a woman.
而且随着越来越多的女性开始从事这些工作，更多的人可能会立刻意识到那个谜题中的外科医生是一位女性。